Guide to the Harry Adams Photographs
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Identified Subjects, 1951–1985
  - Athletes, Sports Teams, and Athletic Events
    - Robinson, Jackie
      - Interior portraits of Jackie Robinson with others at an event, 1968 January 27; 2 photographic prints (Box 1, Folder 51)
      - Interior portrait of Bill Cosby and Jackie Robinson probably in a baseball dugout, circa 1970 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Rose Bowl
      - Interior portraits of Kristina Smith, Rose Bowl Queen for 1985, and others, including a football player, probably at a restaurant, 1984 December; 3 photographic prints (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Roundtree, Richard
      - Interior portrait of Richard Roundtree holding a certificate of appreciation from the City of Los Angeles and posed with a woman and a man, 1974 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - San Francisco Giants
      - Exterior portrait of Ethel Bradley with a member of the San Francisco Giants baseball team, 1975 August (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Simpson, O. J.
      - Interior portrait of O. J. Simpson and another man in a locker room, circa 1968 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Stengel, Casey
      - Exterior views of Casey Stengel throwing the first pitch for game three of the 1965 World Series between the Minnesota Twins and Los Angeles Dodgers at Dodger Stadium in Los Angeles, California, 1965 October 9; 2 photographic prints (Box 1, Folder 57)
      - Exterior portraits during at a "Salute to Casey Stengel" event at Dodger Stadium, which includes retiring the numbers of Roy Campanella, Sandy Koufax, and Jackie Robinson, includes portraits of the honorees as well as Don Newcombe and Jim Gilliam, 1972 June 4; 5 photographic prints (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Teen Post Junior Olympics
      - Exterior view of a marching band at the Teen Post Junior Olympics at the Los Angeles Coliseum, 1966 August 30 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - University of Southern California Football
      - View of the offensive line of the University of Southern California football team on the field during a game, circa 1965 (Box 1, Folder 60)
      - Views of a drum majorette and the University of Southern California marching band, probably on a the field during a halftime show of a football game, circa 1965; 2 photographic prints (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Washington, Kenny
      - Interior portraits from a banquet honoring Kenny Washington, 1970 September 29; 3 photographic prints (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Wooden, John
      - Interior portraits related to John Wooden receiving the Whitney M. Young, Jr. Memorial Award from the Los Angeles Urban League at the Beverly Hilton, 1973 May 31; 2 photographic prints (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Civic Leaders, Groups, and Events
    - Ancient Egyptian Arabic Order Nobles Mystic Shrine
      - Studio portrait of a man wearing regalia for the Ancient Arabic Order of the Nobles of the Mystic Shrine for North America, 1963 November (Box 2, Folder 64)
      - Interior portraits of a banquet for the Ancient Egyptian Arabic Order Nobles Mystic Shrine, Egyptian Temple No. 5, 1973 November; 3 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Co-Opprettes
      - Interior portrait of the Co-Opprettes, a group of ten women and eleven men, 1967 June 1 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Faith Lutheran Church
      - Exterior portraits of Dwight E. Wenger with parishioners of the Faith Lutheran Church in Watts, Los Angeles, California, 1970 March 22; 2 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - First African Methodist Episcopal Church
      - Exterior view of the laying of the cornerstone for the First African Methodist Episcopal Church, 1968; 2 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 68)
      - View of the first cornerstone for the First African Methodist Episcopal Church, Los Angeles, California, 1972 July (Box 2, Folder 69)
      - Exterior portraits related to the dedication of a historic plaque at the site of the First African Methodist Episcopal Church in Los Angeles, 1973 December; 3 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 70)
      - Interior portrait of four women and eight men with a cake during a celebration of the anniversary of the Richard Allen Brotherhood at the First African Methodist Episcopal Church in Los Angeles, 1974 January (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Furlong Track
      - Exterior portraits of women and men, including Gilbert William Lindsay and Leon Washington, related to pioneers of the Furlong Track, circa 1972-1973; 2 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 72)
        The portraits likely occur at different dates
    - Hamilton United Methodist Church
      - Exterior portrait of seventeen women and one man at the Hamilton United Methodist Church, 6330 South Figueroa Street, Los Angeles, California, circa 1958 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Hudson, Elbert T.
      - Interior portrait of Elbert T. Hudson, Marilyn Williams Hudson, Karen Hudson Freeman and Paul C. Hudson, 1966 May 29 (Box 2, Folder 74)
      - Interior portraits of Elbert T. Hudson with a woman and two men, 1967 February; 3 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Human Relations Commission of Los Angeles
      - Interior portraits of award winners at a banquet for the Human Relations Commission of Los Angeles at the Ambassador Hotel including Patricia DeLand, Jack Jones, Marguerite Justice, and Aaron L. Powers, 1970 March 1; 5 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 76)
      - Interior portrait of Gilbert William Lindsay presenting an award to Louise Ridgley at an awards banquet for the Human Relations Commission of Los Angeles, 1971 March 4 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Los Angeles Brotherhood Crusade
      - Exterior view of a parade with an automobile representing the Los Angeles Brotherhood Crusade, 1974 August 18 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Los Angeles Urban League
      - Interior views of a woman singing at a Los Angeles Urban League event, 1976 November; 2 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Mays, Benjamin E.
      - Interior portrait of Benjamin E. Mays receiving an award from two men on behalf of the Second Baptist Church, Los Angeles, California, as well as a portrait with a man and woman, 1971 March 18; 2 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - McGlover, Theo
      - Interior portraits of a banquet honoring Theo McGlover, including McGlover, Eunice McGlover, and Rolland J. Curtis, as well as a woman, possibly Gloria Curtis, 1967 June; 3 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - McLurkin, Thomas
      - Interior portrait of school principal Thomas McLurkin with three women and a man, 1966 March 11 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Neighborhood Adult Participation Project
      - Interior portrait of a boy, three women, and three men, probably related to the Neighborhood Adult Participation Project, 1965 July 27 (Box 2, Folder 83)
      - Interior portrait of Opal C. Jones, executive director of the Neighborhood Adult Participation Project, circa 1965 (Box 2, Folder 84)
      - Interior view of a press conference related to a protest by the Neighborhood Adult Participation Project, 1966 March 28 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Operation Bootstrap
      - Exterior portrait of a group of four women and three men, including Barbara J. Dyce, Gloria Gardner, Robert Hall, and Lew Smith, with a Volkswagen Type 3 donated by Lee Wissler Volkswagen and Feminine Touch Inc. to Operation Bootstrap, 1967 January; 2 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Peace Chapel Missionary Baptist Church
      - Exterior portrait a women and two men, probably including Henry Gibson, looking a building plans for the Peace Chapel Missionary Baptist Church, 1973 July (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - People's Independent Church of Christ
      - Exterior and interior portraits of man related to the construction project for the People's Independent Church of Christ, 1965 July 3; 3 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Price Chapel African Methodist Episcopal
      - Exterior view of the aftermath of a fire at the Price Chapel African Methodist Episcopal church during the morning of August 23, 1973, 1973 August (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Seven Up Youth Foundation
      - Interior portrait of four women, likely winners of a contest sponsored by the Seven Up Youth Foundation, 1965 March 28 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Watts Summer Festival Parade
      - Exterior views men, including Andrew Young, Booker Griffin, Ralph Abernathy, and others, riding in a mule drawn wagon during the Watts Summer Festival, 1968 August; 2 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 91)
      - Exterior portraits of dignitaries during the parade for the annual Watts Summer Festival in the Watts neighborhood of Los Angeles, California, including Ethel Bradley, Tom Bradley, Lillian Lehman, Richard Pryor, and Dennis Weaver, 1973 August 19; 7 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Women's Council of Consolidated Realty Board
      - Interior portraits from an awards banquet of the Women's Council of Consolidated Realty Board including Ethel Bradley, Doris Davis, and Mattye Spivey, at the Ambassador Hotel, Los Angeles, California, 1973 August; 4 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Women's Missionary Society of the African Methodist Episcopal Church
      - Interior view of women and men singing a meeting of the Women's Missionary Society of the African Methodist Episcopal Church at the Los Angeles Hilton, including Rosa Parks, 1971 July 21 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Civil Rights Leaders, Groups, and Events
    - Bond, Julian
      - Interior portrait of Julian Bond in front of a blackboard, 1966 April 15 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Drew Medical Society
      - Exterior views of protestors from the Drew Medical Society, a branch of the National Medical Association, against the Los Angeles County Medical Association for sponsoring a speech by Robert Welch, founder of the John Birch Society, at the Statler Hilton, Los Angeles, California, 1963 September; 2 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Freedom Rally
      - Interior view of the audience at the Freedom Rally at the Los Angeles Sports Arena to raise funds for Freedom Rides, 1961 June 18 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - George Washington Carver Memorial Institute
      - Interior portrait of two women at a George Washington Carver Memorial Institute banquet, 1965 December 2 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Hudson, H. Claude
      - Interior portrait of H. Claude Hudson and a man holding a trophy, 1965 November 1 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - King, Coretta Scott
      - Interior portraits of Coretta Scott King, including a portrait with a woman and man, 1969 November 30; 3 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 100)
      - Interior views from a reception and dinner honoring Coretta Scott King at the Cocoanut Grove, a nightclub at the Ambassador Hotel, Los Angeles, California, 1969 December 2; 3 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 101)
        Images include Coretta Scott King and Sidney Poitier
      - Interior view of Coretta Scott King addressing "A Salute to Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.," banquet at the Beverly Hills Hotel, 1974 January 16 (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - King, Martin Luther, Jr.
      - Exterior views of Martin Luther King, Jr., at a podium addressing the Freedom Rally at Wrigley Field, Los Angeles, California, 1963 May 26; 2 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 103)
      - Interior view of Martin Luther King, Jr., at a pulpit of the First African Methodist Episcopal Church of Los Angeles, with Reverend Hamel Hartford Brookins, 1963 May 26 (Box 2, Folder 104)
      - Interior portrait of Martin Luther King, Jr., with others for with his book, Strength to Love, at an event sponsored by Western Christian Leadership Council, probably at Victory Baptist Church, Los Angeles, California, 1964 February (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - March on Washington for Jobs and Freedom
      - Interior portraits of Harry Belafonte, James Garner, and others at an event at the Ambassador Hotel, Los Angeles, California, supporting the March on Washington for Jobs and Freedom, 1963 August; 2 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Meredith, James
      - Interior portrait of three women with James Meredith, 1963 April; 3 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People
      - Interior portrait of Loren Miller, Roy Wilkins, and Johnny Mathis at a National Association for the Advancement of Colored People event, 1961 October 1; 2 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 108)
      - Exterior view of protestors from the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People United Civil Rights Committee, and other groups, probably to raise awareness of segregation and inequality in the public schools in Los Angeles, California, 1963 September; 2 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 109)
      - Interior portraits of Loren Miller and others at a National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, Los Angeles Branch, event, with an award won by Miller for his legal work, 1964 October 16; 2 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 110)
      - Interior portraits of a banquet honoring Roy Wilkins and his service as executive director of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, which includes H. Claude Hudson and others, at the Statler Hotel, Los Angeles, California, 1965 October 29; 4 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 111)
      - Exterior portrait of Celes King and two men outside the office for the Central Los Angeles branch of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, circa 1967 (Box 2, Folder 112)
      - Interior portraits of a meeting of the Westside Branch of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People and an award to Carl Rowan, 1968; 4 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 113)
      - Interior view of a woman and man dancing at the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Image Awards, 1969 October 11 (Box 2, Folder 114)
      - Interior portraits related to an awards event by the Los Angeles chapter of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, which includes an award given to Stephen Gill Spottswood and a group portrait with Shirley Chisholm and George Brown, 1970 January 8; 3 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 115)
      - Interior portraits of George A. Beavers, Howard Bingham, Rodney Allen Rippy, and Stanley Williford receiving awards from the Los Angeles Chapter of the National Association of Media Women, Inc., 1974 March 24; 4 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 116)
      - Interior views from the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Image Awards, including Bernie Casey, Aretha Franklin, Sidney Poitier, Barry White, and Billy Dee Williams, 1975 January 18; 11 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 117)
      - Interior views from the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Image Awards, including Sidney Poitier with others, 1976 December 1; 3 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 118)
      - Interior views from the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Image Awards, including Diana Ross and a man, 1976 December 1?; 6 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 119)
      - Interior portrait of a man wearing a Million Dollar Club Membership Medal from the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People and receiving an award from the City of Los Angeles on behalf of the organization, 1977 July; 4 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 120)
    - Oyer, Joseph
      - Interior portrait of Joseph Oyer holding a certificate of appreciation from the City of Los Angeles and posed with a woman and a man, 1974 May 17 (Box 2, Folder 121)
    - Protests
      - Exterior views of protesters against the discriminatory practices by developer Don Wilson at the Southwood Riviera Royale housing tract in Torrance, California, 1963 June 16?; 5 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 122)
      - Exterior view of men, probably members of the American Nazi Party, picketing a meeting, circa 1963; 2 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 123)
    - Stars for Freedom
      - Interior portrait of Willie Mays, Will Mastin, and another man for the Stars for Freedom benefit gala at the Santa Monica Civic Center, California, 1963 December 6; 2 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 124)
    - Wilkins, Roy
      - Interior portrait of Roy Wilkins speaking at a microphone, 1972; 2 photographic prints (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - Entertainers and Entertainment Events
    - Allen, Steve
      - Interior portraits from a banquet, including Steve Allen, 1967 February 3; 4 photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 126)
      - Interior portrait Steve Allen and Jayne Meadows receiving the Golden Triangle Award from Billy Mills on behalf of the Young Women's Christian Association of Los Angeles, circa 1971 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Amos, John
      - Interior portrait of John Amos with a woman and a man, circa 1970 (Box 3, Folder 128)
      - Interior view of four men, including John Amos, and two women at the Ambassador Hotel, circa 1970 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Armstrong, Louis
      - Exterior portrait of Louis Armstrong and a woman at Wrigley Field in Los Angeles, California, during the 9th annual Cavalcade of Jazz, 1953 June 7 (Box 3, Folder 130)
      - Interior portrait of Louis Armstrong at a game of the World Series between the Los Angeles Dodgers and the Baltimore Orioles at Dodger Stadium, Los Angeles, California, 1966 October (Box 3, Folder 131)
      - Views from a birthday celebration for Louis Armstrong at the Shrine Auditorium, Los Angeles, including images of Armstrong and a large birthday cake, 1970 July 3; 4 photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Barty, Billy
      - Interior portraits of Billy Barty with women and men, circa 1965; 2 photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Belafonte, Harry
      - Exterior portrait of Harry Belafonte with women and men, circa 1963 (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Brando, Marlon
      - Interior portrait of Marlon Brando with a woman and a man, 1965 February 24 (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Brown, Jim
      - Interior portrait of Jim Brown and a woman, 1976 September (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Browne, Roscoe Lee
      - Interior portrait of Roscoe Lee Browne at a podium, 1972 June (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Burr, Raymond
      - Interior view of Raymond Burr at a podium at the Statler Hotel, Los Angeles, California, 1961 August 11 (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - Caesar, Adolph
      - Interior portrait of Adolph Caesar receiving an award from three women, 1955 March 23 (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Calloway, Cab
      - Interior portrait of Cab Calloway and Zulme "Nuffie" MacNeal Calloway with two women and four men, circa 1981 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Cato, Jim
      - Interior portraits of Jim Cato and a woman wearing a sash with his name, 1975 May; 2 photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - Charles, Ray
      - Exterior portrait of Ray Charles with two boys wearing baseball uniforms and three men, 1965 May 2 (Box 3, Folder 142)
      - Interior portrait of Ray Charles with a woman and two men at the Cocoanut Grove, a nightclub at the Ambassador Hotel, Los Angeles, California, 1968 July 16 (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - Cher and Sonny Bono
      - Interior portrait of Cher and Sonny Bono in a hotel lobby, circa 1972 (Box 3, Folder 144)
    - Cole, Nat King
      - Interior portrait of Nat King Cole and two men, circa 1958 (Box 3, Folder 145)
      - Interior portrait of Nat King Cole with three women and a man, circa 1960 (Box 3, Folder 146)
      - Exterior portraits of men and women leaving the funeral of Nat King Cole at St. James Episcopal Church in Los Angeles, California, including Eddie Anderson, Jack Benny, Vic Damone, Sammy Davis, Jr., Frankie Laine, Peter Lawford, Ricardo Montaban, and Danny Thomas, 1965 February 18; 4 photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 147)
    - Cosby, Bill
      - Interior portrait of Bill Cosby with six women and three men, circa 1970 (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - Crosby, Bing
      - Interior portrait of Bing Crosby and a woman, 1954 January 3 (Box 3, Folder 149)
    - Davis, Sammy, Jr.
      - Interior portraits of attendees of an event, including Sammy Davis, Jr., and Dean Martin at a remodeled Cocoanut Grove, a nightclub at the Ambassador Hotel, Los Angeles, California, 1970 April 17; 5 photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 150)
    - Derek, Bo
      - Interior portrait of Bo Derek, 1985 May (Box 3, Folder 151)
    - Dick Stabile Orchestra
      - View of three women singing with the Dick Stabile Orchestra, circa 1965 (Box 3, Folder 152)
    - Don Johnson's Orchestra
      - Interior view of a guitarist performing with Don Johnson's Orchestra, 1967 June 4 (Box 3, Folder 153)
    - Durante, Jimmy
      - Interior portrait of Jimmy Durante and a man, 1964 April 8 (Box 3, Folder 154)
    - Ellington, Duke
      - Interior portraits of Duke Ellington receiving an commendation award from Los Angeles, Gilbert William Lindsay, Billy Mills, and Charles Williams at the Los Angeles City Hall, 1967 June 29-30; 2 photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 155)
    - Foxx, Redd
      - Interior portraits of Redd Foxx, including him with Billy Dee Williams and Teruko Nakagami Williams as well as a group of six women and three men, circa 1974; 2 photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 156)
    - Gordy, Berry
      - Interior portraits of Berry Gordy with Diana Ross and others at the Cocoanut Grove, a nightclub at the Ambassador Hotel, Los Angeles, California, 1967 June 13; 2 photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 157)
        Images include Berry Gordy and Ben Vereen as well as The Supremes, the music group of Florence Ballard, Diana Ross, and Mary Wilson
    - Grammy Awards
      - Interior portraits at the 9th annual Grammy Awards at the Beverly Hilton Hotel, Los Angeles, California, 1967 March 2; 7 photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 158)
        Images includes portraits of Herb Alpert and Joanie Sommers
      - Interior portraits at the 10th annual Grammy Awards at The Century Plaza Hotel, Los Angeles, California, 1968 February 29; 4 photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 159)
        Images include portraits of Al De Lory and Glen Campbell as well as members of the music group, The 5th Dimension, including Billy Davis Jr., Florence LaRue, Marilyn McCoo, Lamonte McLemore, and Ronald Townson
    - Hayes, Isaac
      - Interior portraits of Isaac Hayes and Mignon Harley, circa 1980; 2 photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 160)
    - Heston, Charlton
      - Interior portraits of Charlton Heston and a woman, 1965 February; 2 photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 161)
    - "King: A Filmed Record... Montgomery To Memphis"
      - Interior portrait of a group involved with the documentary, "King: A Filmed Record... Montgomery To Memphis" probably at a screening of the film, 1970 March 24 (Box 3, Folder 162)
        Group includes Diahann Carroll, Bill Cosby, Sammy Davis, Jr., Ben Gazzara, Charlton Heston, James Earl Jones, Burt Lancaster, Ely Landau, Joseph L. Mankiewicz, Walter Matthau, Sidney Poitier, Anthony Quinn, Leslie Uggams, and Clarence Williams III,
    - KNX Radio Station
      - Interior portrait of four men, probably some of them recording artists with Decca Records, at CBS radio station KNX and its "Matinee" program, circa 1955 (Box 3, Folder 163)
    - Mathis, Johnny
      - Interior portrait of Johnny Mathis and two women, 1964 September (Box 3, Folder 164)
    - McQueen, Steve
      - Exterior portrait of Steve McQueen with Neile Adams and another man, 1964 August (Box 3, Folder 165)
    - Muse, Clarence
      - Interior portraits and overviews of Clarence Muse receiving a awards from the Screen Actors Guild, 1976 September 11; 19 photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 166)
      - Interior portraits of Clarence Muse receiving a recognition award from Tom Bradley, 1976 September 11; 7 photographic prints (Box 3, Folder 167)
    - Onzy Matthews Big Band
      - Interior view of a woman and a man singing with the Onzy Matthews Big Band, 1963 May (Box 3, Folder 168)